Emanuele Sansone

EMAIL: e.sansone@hotmail.it WEBSITE: http://emsansone.github.io/

SUMMARY

I'm passionate in understanding the learning principles governing intelligence. I believe in the existence of a single algorithm underlying the learning process and believe that unsupervised learning represents a good candidate class.

During my doctoral studies, I've focused on analyzing how to exploit unlabeled data in machine learning, providing answers to the following research questions: (i) Is it possible to learn in the context of limited data? (ii) Is it possible to scale existing algorithms for positive-unlabeled learning? (iii) Is it possible to convert the traditional mini-max problem of generative adversarial networks into a single minimization problem?

Besides research, I like the sports world, especially skiing. From 2007, I've been the coach of different local racing ski teams and hold several ski instructor courses. In 2011, I've obtained the diploma of ski master instructor, namely the highest professional Italian degree in alpine skiing. Before that, I've participated as an athlete to many international competitions.

EDUCATION

2013- Ph.D. candidate

ICT doctoral school, University of Trento, Italy

Advisor: Prof. Francesco G.B. De Natale.

My research focuses on machine learning with particular attention to problems like semi-supervised, positive unlabeled, unsupervised and representation learning.

2011-2012 M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Multimodal Photo Galleries Synchronization"

Advisor: Prof. Nicola Conci, Giulia Boato. 110/110 summa cum laude | GpA: 28.82/30

Computer vision application for automatic synchronization of photo galleries from multiple users attending

2008-2010

B.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Master P-NET protocol implementation on PIC 32 architecture"

Advisor: Prof. Dario Petri, Eng. Michele Corrà.

Programming a master device in a network composed by different sensors and actuators. Implementation of P-NET protocol over a PIC 32 microcontroller (C language).

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

2016 Teaching Assistant, Computer Vision (Code 140266)

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Machine Learning for Computer Vision (introduction to statistical learning theory and neural networks).

2015 Teaching Assistant, Multimedia Networking (Code 140151)

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Principles of video compression/coding (useful for transmission/storage of video files).

2015-2016 | Research Intern

LAMDA group, Nanjing University, China

Advisor: Prof. Zhi-Hua Zhou.

I've studied semi-supervised learning as well as positive unlabeled learning.

SPORT EXPERIENCE

2011- Ski master instructor

Italy

Holding several professional education and training courses for ski instructors and candidate ski instructors. This is the highest professional degree in alpine skiing (the total number of ski master instructors in Italy is around 200).

2007- Ski coach

Italy

Coach of young athletes (6-20 years old) in several racing ski teams: Ski Team Sopramonte (2007/2008), Sci Club Padova (2008/2009), Sci Club Panarotta (2009-2011), Ski Team Paganella (2013/2014), Campiglio Ski Team (2016/2017).

2002-2007 | Ski athlete

Italy

See a sample list of records.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATES

SEP 2016 | Academic hardware grant award

Hong Kong, China

Provision of a NVIDIA Titan X GPU Organization: NVIDIA corporation

JAN 2015 | Machine Learning Summer School

Austin, USA

Certificate of attendance

Organization: University of Texas at Austin

Mar 2012 | Merit award

Trento, Italy

Award assigned to distinguished students Organization: University of Trento

Nov 2011 Ski master instructor

Milan, Italy Certificate

Organization: FISI, CoScuMa

SEP 2011 | Ski coach (3° level)

Milan, Italy Certificate

Organization: FISI, STF

MAY 2007 | Ski instructor

Trento, Italy
Certificate
Organization: PAT

PUBLICATIONS

2018 Plummer Autoencoders

E. Sansone, O. T. Phan, F.G.B. De Natale

In review International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)

2017 Training Feedforward Neural Networks with Standard Logistic Activations is Feasible

E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale

In review IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)

2017 Automatic Synchronization of Multi-User Photo Galleries

E. Sansone, K. Apostolidis, N. Conci, G. Boato, V. Mezaris, F.G.B. De Natale

IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM)

2017 Efficient Training for Positive Unlabeled Learning

E. Sansone, F.G.B De Natale, Z.H. Zhou

In review (3rd round) IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)

2016 Classtering: Joint Classification and Clustering with Mixture of Factor Analysers

> E. Sansone, A. Passerini, F.G.B. De Natale European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI)

2014 Synchronizing Multi-User Photo Galleries with MRF

E. Sansone, G. Boato, MS. Dao

MediaEval Workshop

2013 Event Clustering and Classification from Social Media: Watershed-based and Kernel

Methods

TV. Nguyen, MS. Dao, R. Mattivi, E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale, G. Boato

MediaEval Workshop

LANGUAGES

Mothertongue ITALIAN: **ENGLISH:** Fluent (C2) GERMAN: Fluent (B2)

INTERESTS

VOLUNTEERING From 2012 to 2014, I've participated to a no-profit association, GiPro, composed by young representatives

of different sectors (e.g. ski instructors, engineers, lawyers, psychologists). The goal of the association is to promote the professional categories on the territory and stimulate the inter-professional collaboration of young people.

OTHERS I like playing soccer.